<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-09T21:58:57+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Traveller tips website!</title><subtitle>Traveller tips website is a personal blog where I give some special hints and tips for travellers. I try to find most interesting places during my trips for good photo and video materials. If you are a traveller and what to find the most interesting and  sometimes hidden places around the Globe - this website is a great starting point.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Königsstuhl - great nature landscape</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/koenigstuhl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Königsstuhl - great nature landscape" /><published>2018-02-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-02-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/koenigstuhl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/koenigstuhl/">&lt;div class=&quot;download-guide&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/downloads/koenigstuhl_guide.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Download Pocket travelguide&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;Recently I was visiting a very nice place &amp;mdash; the Nationalpark Jasmund reserve on the Rügen island in the north of Germany. One of the most beautiful spots there is so called Königsstuhl &amp;mdash; ”King’s chair”. It is the place where forest meets the sea with high and steep banks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Ruegen island forest&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/ruegen1-bac098116f76f265c2d3ef9b26fca8e7f039108438d73f8c59268cc3aabcde8c.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name of the place goes back to the history, when people choose their king (König) letting the man climb up the bank. So, basically, people with Spiderman’s abilities have become a King. Sad. Anyway, the place is a great photo-spot. On the hill named Königsstuhl there is a small museum with charged entrance of 8.50 EUR. You can check their website &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.koenigsstuhl.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.koenigsstuhl.com&lt;/a&gt;. And here is the first tip:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;tipp&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you come there before or after the museum’s opening/closing times &amp;mdash; you’ve got a free entrance and, most probably, the silence without visitors. It is a cool time to film the sunrise (the sun will be over the see  so the banks will be nicely lighted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get there, I bet you will want to go down the sea, especially if you travel in summer. This is what happened with me &amp;mdash; when I got the place I was exhausted and it was very hot. After an hour of the forest walk and unsuccessful navigation with Google maps I started to talk with myself, but didn’t lose the passion to get the sea. And finally &amp;mdash; yea! I found the way to the beach, so here is an exact map for you to safely get to the sea.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;map&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Map&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/maps/hohenzollern_mariazell-6c0d096a8ab3530564249c9c21d3de356d6479e8a3e0f35816502c83752413af.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;overlay&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        
            &lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/search/?api=1&amp;query=Hechingen-Boll%2C+Mariazell&amp;query_place_id=ChIJ5apUM6YDmkcRzwwm8OualSE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
                Open in Google maps    
            &lt;/a&gt;
              

    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;It was around 7 p.m. and I was totally alone there (if you don’t count ducks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would really recommend the place if you like to be alone with the nature or your aim is to have great nature photos without fussy tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Schwerin Land museum&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/ruegen2-cbe1732ffa1052304a8d09d6ccdab6c1acdb0b259367ead74c86e8b4f32f3a88.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just be aware, that the water is very cold there. So, if you're up to swimming, i would not recommend to go there alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;travellertips&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Traveller tips&lt;/h2&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;When is the best time to visit&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;bla&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Best places to stay&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;bla&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;The way you can go around&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;bla&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Suggested daily budget&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Useful resources&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;bla&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="nature" /><category term="photospot" /><summary type="html">Download Pocket travelguide</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Treasure found</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/schwerin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Treasure found" /><published>2018-01-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/schwerin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/schwerin/">&lt;div class=&quot;download-guide&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/downloads/schwerin_guide.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Download Pocket travelguide&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;I trapped to this great photo-spot accidentally during my trip to the german city Schwerin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Schwerin Land museum&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/schwerin1-156dcbdd5397d671c7634faedc824fbef6a2c34bfe21fdd9f2b5ebc47c8abb5a.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find this photo-treasure you should go to the small Land-museum (anchor) near Schwerin. If you travel by car &amp;mdash; there is no problem to navigate there. You can park the car directly around the corner from the entrance. If you travel by transport, simply take the Bus # from Schwerin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;map&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Map&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/maps/hohenzollern_mariazell-6c0d096a8ab3530564249c9c21d3de356d6479e8a3e0f35816502c83752413af.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;overlay&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        
            &lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/search/?api=1&amp;query=Hechingen-Boll%2C+Mariazell&amp;query_place_id=ChIJ5apUM6YDmkcRzwwm8OualSE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
                Open in Google maps    
            &lt;/a&gt;
              

    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 

&lt;section class=&quot;tipp&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can get a permission of making drone-photography at the entrance if you assure of non-commercial usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum itself is a very nice place to be. + (description of the museum).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;tipp&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you already on place you should definitely visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fischereihof-muess.de&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fischereihof Mueß Inh. Gerd Eberwein&lt;/a&gt; if you’re up to fish. You can find very nice cooked or fresh fish to buy there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Schwerin Land museum&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/schwerin3-c5a0a37a2a8a6d1237055e8dc70434e9686b440875f99bcb6a96511c734108e6.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You allowed even make a small picnic (of course without fire) on its territory. There is small cafe, where you can taste homemade food and pastry. To be honest &amp;mdash; the place doesn’t look like a touristic spot &amp;mdash; and this makes it so nice ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go further opposite to the entrance you will come to the shore of the huge lake &amp;mdash; you will notice the ship right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Schwerin Land museum&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/schwerin2-c24dbe835ea7f8307ed5e190839e116e5d1cb235156ae46ae4f5b5dc2fa98dd2.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a great spot for abandoned places lovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;travellertips&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Traveller tips&lt;/h2&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;When is the best time to visit&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I would say that the best time is summer, as you can have a picnic on the grass and swim in the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Best places to stay&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The closest and quite cheap hotel is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feriendorf-muess.de/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Feriendorf Muess&lt;/a&gt;. In general, you’ll find hundreds of other options around Schwerin &amp;mdash; just choose one according your budget and wishes.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;The way you can go around&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you travel &lt;b&gt;by car&lt;/b&gt; you can go by Autobahn A 24 Berlin-Hamburg in the direction Schwerin, then by the road A 14 you will be directly there: with the exit Schwerin Ost go out from Autobahn and follow the Bundesstraße 321 approximately 1,5 km in direction Schwerin/Zentrum. Shortly after passing the city entrance sign, turn right at the traffic lights (Netto Markt). After 350 meters you will see at the right the hotel Feriendorf Muess and the next street left &amp;mdash; is the museum.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you go by &lt;b&gt;public transport&lt;/b&gt; from Schwerin, you can start at the main railway station (Schweriner Hauptbahnhof). There you take a tram No 1 in the direction of the Hegelstraße and go to the stop called Stauffenbergstraße. There you change to the Bus No 6 in the direction of the  Muess Ausbau and go to the Freilichtmuseum stop. There you can easely find a way to the Museum.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Suggested daily budget&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you visit the place alone you don’t need much money. The entrance price is just 5 EUR for adult, 0-2 EUR for kids and 10 EUR for a family. To get from Schwerin to Museum will cost you 2.80 EUR in one way or you can take a day ticket for Zone 1 and Zone 2 for 8.40 EUR. Other details you can find on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nahverkehr-schwerin.de/tarif/tarifubersicht/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Schwerin Public Transport website&lt;/a&gt;. If we assume that you start your trip from Schwerin, having 3 meals per diem in middle-range or fast-food restaurants, and have a night in hotel of economy class, the your total budget would start at &lt;b&gt;~75 EUR&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Useful resources&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schwerin.de/kultur-tourismus/kunst-kultur/bildende-kunst-museen/freilichtmuseum-schwerin-muess/oeffnungszeiten-preise-anfahrt/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Information about Museum&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nahverkehr-schwerin.de/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Schwerin Public Transport website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="abandoned" /><category term="photospot" /><summary type="html">Download Pocket travelguide</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hohenzollern visit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hohenzollern/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hohenzollern visit" /><published>2017-09-29T09:24:03+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-29T09:24:03+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hohenzollern</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hohenzollern/">&lt;div class=&quot;download-guide&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/downloads/hohenzollern_guide.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Download Pocket travelguide&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;h2&gt;History of the Castle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most beautiful medieval castles of Germany is Hohenzollern Castle. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burg-hohenzollern.com/castle-history.html&quot; tagret=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt; of the 750 years-old castle is quite interesting. First mention about the place dates to the 11&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. Before it was destroyed completely in 1423, the Castle had a very prominent value for the region. It was called &quot;Crown of all Castles in Swabia&quot;. The second Hohenzollern Castle that was more fortified and bigger started its life in 1454. During the Dark Ages it changed many owners and got ruined till the beginning of 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1850 King Frederick William IV started reconstruction of the Castle. One of his ideas was to make this place habitant again, which is still the case till our days. Currently the castle is a private property of Hohenzollern dynasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view of the castle is spectacular! Its gothic style reveals some unknown romantic feeling. The landscape around makes the place even more attractive to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Hohenzollern castle view&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/hohenzollern_top-cf6a0c551658b29f648a183a8b243760e15b2feafd73300d9610f2fa3dab8ec4.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to get the place&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;tipp&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you want to visit this great place, your start point can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuttgart&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stuttgart&lt;/a&gt;. From there you should take the regional train to Hechingen. You should plan your day in advance, as the direct regional train departures approximately every 2 hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price for the train ticket from Stuttgart to Hechingen was 19 EUR for me. You can check and book the tickets &lt;a href=&quot;http://reiseauskunft.bahn.de/bin/query2.exe/dn?ld=15073&amp;seqnr=2&amp;ident=6l.0190673.1497683751&amp;rt=1&amp;rememberSortType=minDeparture&amp;HWAI=JS!ajax=yes!js=yes!&amp;REQ0HafasScrollDir=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hechingen is very quiet small town and there is no problem to find the right direction. When you step out from the train, you can go to the back of the station &amp;mdash; from there you already see the castle on the hill. There are two ways to get the castle: shuttle bus (departures every hour from the bus station that is right near the railway station) or a taxi (~15 EUR). In my case it was a taxi, as I had not much time and planned to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH7L30qgetc/?taken-by=polinovskyi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;another German castle&lt;/a&gt; next morning. Another benefit to take a taxi &amp;mdash; is that you can ask driver to stop on the spot which is great for a nice photo. Taxi or shuttle bus drives you to the parking space that is about 10 minutes from the castle. There you can use the toilet and find some snacks as well as the tourist information. And yes, I am writting here about the toilet. Ha-ha. When you travel, sometimes it's a hell to find a &quot;rest place&quot;. There are two options to get the castle from parking: by foot or by castle shuttle bus. Ticket for the shuttle to the castle costs 2 EUR for an adult. I would recommend a bus, as you’re going to save some power to go to the view point ;) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Inside Hohenzollern castle&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/hohenzollern2-4ff91424310826cec47c4d15b2d649d83eacfbf211af020718d2fd47c8fb0d12.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the castle you can go for a guided tour or walk yourself. If you're hungry or desperately in the need of a cup of coffee, you can sit at small caffee on its territory and eat some snack there. It is quite interesting in the castle itself - significant picture gallery, many treasures including Prussian King’s Crown. But the most mesmerizing there &amp;mdash; is the view that opens for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;tipp&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be aware, that drones are prohibited on the territory of the castle and the nearby area as the castle is a private property and by German law you're not allowed to film a private property. You can try to get an official permission, but it will not be easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting around and buying a magnet for your fridge &amp;mdash; you might want to go here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Hohenzollern castle view&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/hohenzollern4-5629388fee9da31796ec0c43ae7980e25f316a1f9dbfb599d957d8bd1620b3f3.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s go to a magnificent view point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go out from the castle's gates and start to go back by the shuttle’s road, in 200-300m you would see the small arrow sign pointing left off the road in the forest. You should follow the signs with &quot;Mariazell&quot; (first checkpoint of our route) or &quot;Zellerhorn&quot; (our destination point). If the weather is rainy or you go right after the rain &amp;mdash; be prepared, the forest path is very slippery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, our first point is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;location-address&quot;&gt;
    Hechingen-Boll, Mariazell &lt;br&gt;
    Unnamed Road, 72379 Hechingen
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;map&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Map&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/maps/hohenzollern_mariazell-6c0d096a8ab3530564249c9c21d3de356d6479e8a3e0f35816502c83752413af.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;overlay&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        
            &lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/search/?api=1&amp;query=Hechingen-Boll%2C+Mariazell&amp;query_place_id=ChIJ5apUM6YDmkcRzwwm8OualSE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
                Open in Google maps    
            &lt;/a&gt;
              

    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;This is what you expect to see there:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Mariazell Church&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/hohenzollern3-65201d18d735d03e15be19f84f72a18b9599a558714f890e197e02169d9e5198.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the church the path to Zellerhorn have noticeable incline to the top of the hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So our destination point is &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;location-address&quot;&gt;
Zellerhornwiese &lt;br&gt;
72461 Albstadt 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;map&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Map&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/maps/hohenzollern_zellerhorn-880872c34c5898b7f29efdabfef462e6ad760da7bd5937355367f545a6a7babd.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;overlay&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        
            &lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/search/?api=1&amp;query=zellernhornwiese&amp;query_place_id=ChIJhTyJzKYDmkcRgN0LsJ0d9to&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
                Open in Google maps    
            &lt;/a&gt;
              

    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;There you can relax and make great photos! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few more viewpoints are available around as well, like &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;location-address&quot;&gt;
    Aussichtspunkt Hohenzollernblick &lt;br&gt;
    72379 Albstadt
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to get the most prominent experience of the place, I would recommend this route&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;map&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Map&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/maps/hohenzollern_route-fb7978bcb34f07b9c7995ee2fa61250452f27f8a9cc0cd9d16d1b359ccb62fb8.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;overlay&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        
            &lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/dir/?api=1&amp;origin=hohenzollern+castle&amp;origin_place_id=ChIJ9Z59XbEDmkcRL1pF2TBwziI&amp;waypoints=Hechingen-Boll%2C+Mariazell%7Czellernhornwiese&amp;waypoint_place_ids=ChIJ5apUM6YDmkcRzwwm8OualSE%7CChIJhTyJzKYDmkcRgN0LsJ0d9to&amp;destination=Aussichtspunkt+Hohenzollernblick&amp;destination_place_id=ChIJazDxRA0DmkcRA3_rhAPSmoE&amp;travelmode=walking&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
                Open in Google maps    
            &lt;/a&gt;
              

    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 

&lt;section class=&quot;travellertips&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Traveller tips&lt;/h2&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;When is the best time to visit&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you want to have great photos of the place, I would recommend to go in autumn (because of colors) or in winter with snow.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;How you get the place&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From Stuttgart, take regional train IRE (check the connection at &lt;a href=&quot;bahn.de&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bahn.de&lt;/a&gt;). From Hechingen railway station take a shuttle bus (approx. every 2 hours) or taxi. You can use special tickets if you travel in group or want to visit Stuttgart region, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metropolticket.de/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;metropolticket.de&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bahn.de/regional/view/regionen/bawue/freizeit/bawue_ticket.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Baden-Württemberg-Ticket&lt;/a&gt;.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you drive by car… &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Other useful information and time tables you find on the website of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burg-hohenzollern.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hohenzollern Castle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Kind of clothes you should pack&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you travel in a warm time it’s better to have one or two additional T-shirts. As you climb to a photo-spot it could be quite warm in the forest.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;The way you can go around&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It is quite simple to get a place with public transport, but if you like to travel with car, here are awesome resource to find one in the region: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rentalcars.com/en/city/de/stuttgart/&quot;&gt;Rent a car in Stuttgart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Suggested daily budget&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assuming you travel with public transport only, have food in fast-food restaurants, your minimal day budget will be &lt;b&gt;around 56 EUR&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This includes: &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Public transport, including regional train connections: (Stuttgart-Hechingen-Stuttgart): 24 EUR if you use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bahn.de/regional/view/regionen/bawue/freizeit/bawue_ticket.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Baden-Württemberg-Ticket&lt;/a&gt; (21 EUR if you are under 27 years old).&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Food, if you eat in middle-class or fast-food restaurants - 20 EUR&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Castle entrance ticket (7 EUR - entrance to the castle's area, 12 EUR - visit also interior rooms of the castle, so we assume MAX-program here ;) )&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Useful resources&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The most useful resource in this case is the official &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burg-hohenzollern.com/startpage.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hohenzollern Castle Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To plan your route, you can use also very nice tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goeuro.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;goeuro.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="castle" /><category term="photospot" /><summary type="html">Download Pocket travelguide</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Get to the exclusion zone without the permit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/zone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get to the exclusion zone without the permit" /><published>2017-08-29T09:24:03+02:00</published><updated>2017-08-29T09:24:03+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/zone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/zone/">&lt;p&gt;If you are about stalking &amp;mdash; you can easily get to the Exclusion Zone in the Chernobyl region. This is not a Chernobyl itself, but the place is within the 30km alienation area and already a place to feel the Stuff. And… may be you meet some mutants there, who knows ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;tipp&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Please note that this trip can be quite tricky. Official law says: &quot;During passing the Zone you should not leave your vehicle, otherwise you will violate the law&quot;. But you always have an option... you know, you wanna pee ;) Or you can drive through without stops which will any way be an experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Exclusion zone&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/stalker1-61937474f0a302cc9fbae53b30dd19ee8ae22ce2176aa952bb9f7c9ea0522777.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our destination is Polisske city - an abandoned town in the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone, part of Kyiv Oblast in Ukraine: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;map&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;Map&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/maps/zone_poliske-63379089b2ea728e2f8a72a8efdc7d03c7416aeb62d5c9a99f4d546cb373f24c.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;overlay&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
        
            &lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/search/?api=1&amp;query=Poliske,+Kyivs'ka+oblast,+Ukraine&amp;query_place_id=ChIJzbTeoxVHKkcRcVCtKTi5RyE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
                Open in Google maps    
            &lt;/a&gt;
              

    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you go there, you should be kind of prepared. First of all, you should be aware &amp;mdash; that this is an exclusion zone, thus there is a remaining radioactive fallout contamination. However, if your goal is to be shiny at night &amp;mdash; this is the place to be! Ok, joking &amp;mdash; the risk is not high in this region. It is also known that there are some people living in the ghost city (round ten people). Because it’s a closed area there are a lot of wild animals and flocks of dogs. I would recommend to have something like sound-device to scare dogs (you can buy &lt;a href=&quot;https://de.aliexpress.com/item/LED-Ultrasonic-Pet-Dog-Repeller-Anti-Barking-Stop-Bark-Training-Device-Trainer-Hot-Sale/32801515354.html?spm=a2g0x.search0104.3.2.VgDoma&amp;ws_ab_test=searchweb0_0,searchweb201602_5_10320_10152_10321_10151_10065_10344_10068_10342_10547_10343_10322_10340_10548_10341_10193_10194_10084_10083_10304_10615_10307_10302_10180_10059_10314_10184_10534_100031_10319_10604_10103_10186_10142,searchweb201603_36,ppcSwitch_7&amp;algo_expid=2e39d20c-0784-462a-af29-8c4e9d1360e5-0&amp;algo_pvid=2e39d20c-0784-462a-af29-8c4e9d1360e5&amp;transAbTest=ae803_5&amp;priceBeautifyAB=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;at aliexpress&lt;/a&gt;) or some fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; The trick to get the place without an official permission is that the 7km of the regional road (P02) goes through the Zone itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Exclusion zone&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/stalker2-6ce9db8fe002e88183c8a03413436b0cd7d00949019a8b5e75e87d990facbc3f.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go there, you should go by some transport and better to be accompanied with ukrainian (or russian-) speaking person because you will have a short talk at the checkpoint: you probably will be asked for your documents and your destination. You just say that you go to the Ovruch city (if you start from Kiev) or vice versa. You can also say that you’re a special american agent if you want to have some fun :) Ok, better not, as our goal is an abandoned town. At this point you should hide all your cameras, as making photos are officially prohibited. However, when I was there I got a word permission to get some snaps from that guys at the checkpoint. So, things are not that scary and serious as you can first think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img alt=&quot;Exclusion zone&quot; src=&quot;/assets/posts/stalker-792d1a195103c9d3dface8795329f9dc0d8cf970410b288516393b1629cda7ea.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as you pass the checkpoint you will get to the quiet ghost town... If you want to get more experience &amp;mdash; you should get off the way and leave your car in a way that it’s hidden for other road users. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this video you can check what would be your experience in the city itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qTkS-tpAcXQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;small&gt;Video made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChZRCUPNCaZh3FCSI66TpWA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;som3e&lt;/a&gt;. For more info please refer to: &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.pripyat.de&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;forum.pripyat.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really recommend this place, as this is that kind of places that stay with you forever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;travellertips&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Traveller tips&lt;/h2&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;When is the best time to visit&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It depends on your preferences &amp;mdash; if you go there to feel some darkness and make the photos that are emotionally strong &amp;mdash; then a late autumn or winter is the best time.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;How you get the place&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Equipment to have&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Special equipment is not required, but remember that the region is wild for many years. It is better to have some &lt;a href=&quot;https://de.aliexpress.com/item/LED-Ultrasonic-Pet-Dog-Repeller-Anti-Barking-Stop-Bark-Training-Device-Trainer-Hot-Sale/32801515354.html?spm=a2g0x.search0104.3.2.VgDoma&amp;ws_ab_test=searchweb0_0,searchweb201602_5_10320_10152_10321_10151_10065_10344_10068_10342_10547_10343_10322_10340_10548_10341_10193_10194_10084_10083_10304_10615_10307_10302_10180_10059_10314_10184_10534_100031_10319_10604_10103_10186_10142,searchweb201603_36,ppcSwitch_7&amp;algo_expid=2e39d20c-0784-462a-af29-8c4e9d1360e5-0&amp;algo_pvid=2e39d20c-0784-462a-af29-8c4e9d1360e5&amp;transAbTest=ae803_5&amp;priceBeautifyAB=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dog repeller&lt;/a&gt; or some fireworks that make sound.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Best places to stay&lt;/h3&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;The way you can go around&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;How to get visa&lt;/h3&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Suggested daily budget&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Useful resources&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;bla&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h3&gt;Helpful vocabulary&lt;/h3&gt;
    
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Hello &amp;mdash; Добрий день (dobryj den’)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;I am driving to Kiev &amp;mdash; Я їду до Києва (ya yidu do Kyjeva)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;How much does it costs? &amp;mdash; Скільки це коштує (Skil’ky tse koshtuje)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="abandoned" /><category term="photospot" /><summary type="html">If you are about stalking &amp;mdash; you can easily get to the Exclusion Zone in the Chernobyl region. This is not a Chernobyl itself, but the place is within the 30km alienation area and already a place to feel the Stuff. And… may be you meet some mutants there, who knows ;)</summary></entry></feed>